Guide to the Sara Hickman collection, 1978-2017 MS 718
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Sara Hickman collection
1978-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hickman, Sara
MS 718
9 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
0.592 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS0718aip_001 (0.592 GB)
13.2 Gigabytes (Nearline access: MS0718aip_002 (13.2 GB)
This collection consists of business records, photographs, audio, newspaper clippings, and correspondence documenting the music career of Sara Hickman.
Biographical / Historical
Sara Hickman grew up in Houston, Texas and attended the famed High School for the Performing and Visual Arts [HSPVA] in the late 1970s. For college, she moved away from Houston to attend North Texas State University (University of North Texas) and graduated with a BA in painting in 1986. After graduation, she relocated to Dallas and embarked on her musical career, playing at venues like Uncle Calvin's, Club Dada, and Poor David's Pub.
After recording and promoting her first album "Equal Scary People," Hickman signed with Elektra. While with the major label, she re-released that album and put out a new one, "Shortstop." Due to a variety of factors, she parted ways with the company in 1993.
Since her third album masters were Elektra property, she raised money from family, friends, and fans to buy back her masters and went on to release her fourth album, "Necessary Angels." Around the same time, she formed the trio Domestic Science Club with Robin Macy, formerly of the Dixie Chicks, and Patty Lege, which ended up putting out two albums.
In 1995, she left Dallas for Austin and has lived there ever since. She released 15 more albums over the next 20 years, including four children's albums. In 2010, the Texas State Commission on the Arts named her the Official Texas State Musician.
Since her days at HSPVA, Sara has devoted her time to a myriad of charitable activities including Habitat for Humanity, House the Homeless, Race for the Cure, and the Uganda Fistula Foundation. While she retired from music in 2017, she still continues her charity work and does vocal work for national commercials.
Content Description
This collection contains business records, correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, audio, teaching materials, memorabilia, correspondence, and other items documenting the music career of Sara Hickman. It is divided into seven series.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Sara Hickman in July 2017.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Music; Politics and government
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
Subjects (Persons)
Hickman, Sara
- Series I: General, 1982-2017
  - "Absence of Blame", 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - African choir (CD), 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alliance of Artists and Recording Companies, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Amazing Faith of Texas", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1989-2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Awards programs, 1988-2010 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Big Kid", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Big Kid" and kid song ideas (cassette tape), 2000s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biography, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BMI, 1988-2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bob-A-Lew Music, 2006-2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cafe Press, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Calendar, 1989-01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Certificates, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Charity work, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Charts and radio play, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Chord charts/String arrangements, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Clawmaster", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Commercials, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Communications proposals, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Consulting, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Copyrighted songs, 1990-1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - incoming, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - outgoing, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Domestic Science Club, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Elektra, 1989-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - esta chica, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Equal Scary People", 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Equal Scary People" song book, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Faithful Heart", 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fan mail, 1980s-2010s (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Fan web site, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fliers, 1980-2010s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Flyer Tour with Nanci Griffith, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Half Price Books, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Harry Fox Agency licensing, 2001-2005 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "I Couldn't Help Myself" - sheet music, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Intellitoys, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Journal - lyrics, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Licensing, 2003-2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Loophole Management, 1988-2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lyrics, 1980s-2010s (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Lyrics not by Hickman, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lyrics unfinished, 1980s-2010s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - MCA, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - MCA/Universal, 1990-2012 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Mechanical licenses, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Motherlode", 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Music supervisor, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Necessary Angels", 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Necessary Angels" correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Newborn", 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - News clippings, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - News clippings, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - News clippings, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - News clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - News clippings, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - News clippings, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - News clippings, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - News clippings, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - News clippings, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - News clippings, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - News clippings, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - News clippings, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - News clippings, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - News clippings, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - News clippings, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - News clippings, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - News clippings, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - News clippings, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - News clippings, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - News clippings, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - News clippings, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - News clippings, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - News clippings, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - News clippings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Note cards, 1980s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Online sales, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Oral history, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Performances, 2003-2008 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Le Petit Bonheur, 1997-2009 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Plaques, 1980s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Poetry, 1980s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Politics, 1988-2007 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Postcards, 1990s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Private performances, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Product endorsements, 1992-2006 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Promotional analysis, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - References, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Rhino Pure, 2000-2012 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - RightsFlow, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Set lists, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sexism in music, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Shanachie Entertainment, 1996-2007 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Sheet music, 1980s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "Shortstop", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Simply" sheet music, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Sound Exchange, 2006-2010 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Southwest Airlines, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "Spiritual Appliances", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - State Musician of Texas, 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Super Pal Universe (CDs), 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 51-52)
  - "Take It Like a Man", 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Texas Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Texas Music Office, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Theatre, ca. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Tickets, 1990s-2010s (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Toddler", 2001 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Tour, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - TV engagements, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Two Kinds of Laughter", 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Walk to Emmaus (photographs), 2000-11 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Warner Music Discovery, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Will Taylor string arrangements, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Windham Hill, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Writings, ca. 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series II: Teaching materials, 1992-2015
  - Assorted speeches, 2000s-2010s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Assorted teaching materials, 2000s-2010s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Central Market Cooking School, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Childhood talks (2 CDs), 2007 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Creative Camp, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Creativity classes, ca. 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Early Childhood Methodist Conference, 2006-02 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Family Time Rocks! In Tune with the Universe, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kerrville Folk Festival - professional development program, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Music industry talks, ca. 2006 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Music therapy, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Songwriting classes, 2010-2015 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Speaking engagements, 2003-2011 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Spiritual talks, ca. 2006 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - St. Mark's presentation correspondence, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Women-focused courses, ca. 2011 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series III: Books/Journals, 1981-2009
  - "epiphany," Volume 4, Spring 1981 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - "The Green Fuse", Spring 1985 (Box 4, Item 2)
  - "The Green Fuse", Spring 1986 (Box 4, Item 3)
  - "The Book of Smiles," Cindy Cashman, 2003 (Box 4, Item 4)
  - "The Sweater Book: Hundreds of People... One Common Thread," Stephen Mosher, 2003 (Box 4, Item 5)
  - "my little red book," Rachel Kauder Nalebuff, 2009 (Box 4, Item 6)
  - "Top Dogs and Their Pets," David Woo and Richard Michael Pruitt, 2009 (Box 4, Item 7)
  - "An Eclectic Array of Texas Musicians Coloring Book!", 2019 (Box 4, Item 8)
- Series IV: Photographs/Negatives/Slides, 1978-2010s
  - Album photo shoots, 1990-2000s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Bands, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Domestic Science Club, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Equal Scary People" scrapbook, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Group photographs, 1980s-2010s (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
  - Group photographs without Sara Hickman, 1980s-2010s (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Necessary Angels" party, 1994-06-24 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Negatives, 1980s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Performances (2 CDs), 1980s-2010s (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Performances - proof sheets, 1980s-2000s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1978-2000s (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publicity photographs, 1990s-2000s (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Publicity proofs, 1990s-2000s (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Slides, 1980s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series V: Audio and Video, 1980-2014
  - Sub-Series A: Video
    - KVUE, 2003 (Box 6)
    - "Motherlode" official CD release party, 2006 (Box 6)
    - "Big Bird, Little Bird", 2010 (Box 6)
    - The Blue Door live, 2011 (Box 6)
  - Sub-Series B: 1/4" reel-to-reel audio
    - "How Can It Be"; "As Musch As Me", 1986-06 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People" - outtakes, 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Salvador", 1989 (Box 6)
  - Sub-Series C: 12" LPs
    - The High School for the Performing and Visual Arts Vocal Department in Concert, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People" test pressings, 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People", 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People" single, 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Legacy: A collection of New Folk Music", 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Shortstop", 1990 (Box 6)
  - Sub-Series D: Cassette Tapes
    - "Equal Scary People", 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People" (2), 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Equal Scary People" single, 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Shortstop", 1990 (Box 6)
    - "I Couldn't Help Myself" single, 1990 (Box 6)
    - "Blue Eyes Are Sensitive to the Light" single (2), 1990 (Box 6)
    - "New Music for a New Decade", 1990 (Box 6)
    - Clever Pennies - "One Big Mystery", 1990 (Box 6)
    - "Romania" single, 1993-01-30 (Box 6)
    - "Domestic Science Club", 1993 (Box 6)
    - "Skin Feathers & Fur" single, 1994 (Box 6)
    - "Ready to Pop!", 1996 (Box 6)
  - Sub-Series E: CDs
    - "Equal Scary People", 1988 (Box 7)
      Scope and Contents
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Equal Scary People," "Simply," "Last Night Was a Big Rain," "Meant to Be," "500x The Train Song," "Why Don't You," "I Wish I Were a Princess," "Take It Like a Man," "This Is a Man's World," "Song for My Father," "Under the Sycamore Tree," "Take It Like a Man (Reprise)"
    - "Equal Scary People", 1989 (Box 7)
    - "Legacy: A Collection of New Folk Music", 1989 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Salvador"
    - WEA music sampler, 1989-11 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Equal Scary People"
    - "Arachnophobia" soundtrack, 1990 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Blue Eyes Are Sensitive to the Light"
    - "Blue Eyes Are Sensitive to the Light" single, 1990 (Box 7)
    - "Decadent Music", 1990 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Decadent"
    - Kirk Edens - "Rising on the Wind", 1990 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "I Know"
    - "In the Fields" single, 1990 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "In the Fields"
    - "The Very Thing" single, 1990 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "The Very Thing"
    - Chuck Jackson and Cissy Houston - "I'll Take Care of You" (percussion work), 1992 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Looking for a Love," "Always on My Mind," "I Don't Want to Cry," "Why Do You Turn Away," "Take Me Back I'm Sorry," "Are You Lonely for Me Baby," "I Wanna Be with You," "Waiting in Vain," "I'll Take Good Care of You," "You Make Me Feel Brand New"
    - Domestic Science Club, 1993 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Secrets of Love," "I Love You," "Working Man," "Sweet Tooth," "Talk to Me," "Kayaking," "Windmill and the Wind," "Tenderness Place," "Peaches 'n Cream," "Winter Wonderland"
    - "Kikusuimaru Meets Brave Combo", 1993 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Track information is in Japanese.
    - "Too Good to Be Left Behind!", 1993 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Everyone Goes to the Moon"
    - Colin Boyd - "Juliet", 1994 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "This Heart"
    - "The Met", 1994 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Tiger in a Teacup Town"
    - "The Moose New Music Sampler: Sole Music", 1994 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "A Room of One's Own"
    - "Necessary Angels", 1994 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Pursuit of Happiness," "Shadowboxing," "The Best of Times," "Sister and Sam," "Time Will Tell," "Eye of the Storm," "Oh Daddy," "Room of One's Own," "Tiger in a Teacup Town," "Slippery," "Joy," "The Place Where the Garage Used to Stand Kookooobura"
    - John Alan - "The Worst" (vocal work), 1995 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Let Me Die in Angora"
    - "Kerrville Folk Festival 1995 Highlights" (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Sweet Tooth," Trout Fishing in America - "No Matter What Goes Right"
    - "The Women of Kerrville", 1995 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Peaches and Cream"
    - Domestic Science Club - "Three Women", 1996 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Three Women," "Reserved for the One I Love," "Ain't Seen Nothing Yet," "Why Don't You," "Windmill and the Wind," "Unseen Angels," "Sincerity," "Time of Innocence," "When You Hold Me," "I Want to be Bad," "Goodbye and So Long to You," "Taxi to Your Heart," "Blue Diamond Minds," "Give It Every Little Thing You've Got," "Calm of Your Heart," "What a Little Moonlight Can Do"
    - "Ready to Pop" (2), 1996-06-22 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Tiger in a Teacup Town," "One in Our Happiness," "Aurora," "Kayaking," "If We Send Our Hearts over Now," "In the Fields," "500x the Train Song," "Joy," "Take Whatever I Can Get," "This Heart"
    - "107.1 KGSR Broadcasts, vol. 6", 1998 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: Lyle Lovett - "White Freight Liner Blues," "Eight Ball," Robert Earl Keen - "Merry Christmas from the Family"
    - Austin Lounge Lizards - "Employee of the Month" (vocal work), 1998 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Leonard Cohen's Day Job"
    - "Big League Babe: The Christine Lavin Tribute Album, Pt. 2", 1998 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "The Dakota"
    - "Newborn" master, 1999-07-16 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Includes 6 untitled tracks.
    - "Newborn", 1999 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Hush," "It's Alright a Capella," "A-Tisket A-Tasket," "Lily," "Goops in It," "This Heart," "Reserved for the One I Love," "Big Bird Little Bird," "Moonshadow," "You Are My Sunshine," "A Slice of Heaven," "All Things Bright and Beautiful," "It's Alright with Strings," "We Are Each Other's Angels," "Brahms Lullaby"
    - "The Chapel Chorale of First United Methodist Church", 2000 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "23rd Psalm," "All Are Welcome," "Freely," "Haleluyah Pelo Tsa Roma," "Illuminated by Your Light," "Night of Silence," "Parce Domino," "Siyahmba," "Without Seeing You," "He Has the Power"
    - "The Million Mom March Album", 2000 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "We Are Each Other's Angels"
    - "One Flower to the Left" cover only, 2000 (Box 7)
    - "Spiritual Appliances" (2), 2000 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Standing Ground," "Life," "Kerosene," "Edward," "Woman Waiting to Happen," "I Wish I Could Run," "Everything's Red," "Dear Tracey," "Moment of Grace," "Bowl of Stars," "Come Around," "We Are EAch Other's Angels," "I'm Not Going Anywhere"
    - Christmas master, 2001 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Have Yourself a Merry Little Christmas," "Silent Night," "The Last Month of the Year," "Frosty the Snowman," "Angels Among Us," "Santa Clause Is Coming to Town," "The Reason We Have Christmas in the World Lil Bits Lullaby," "Kiss This Christmas Goodbye." Digital folder labeled x-mas_2001.
    - "Equal Scary People", 2001 (Box 7)
    - "Just One Race" (2), 2001 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Just One Race"
    - "Listen to the Radio" single, 2001-04-26 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Listen to the Radio"
    - "This Christmas Wish" single, 2001 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Have Yourself a Merry Little Christmas," "Silent Night," "The Last Month of the Year," "Frosty the Snowman," "Angels Among Us," "Santa Claus Is Coming to Town," "The Reason We Have Christmas in the World Lil Bits Lullaby," "Kiss This Christmas Goodbye"
    - "Songs and stories with Sara Hickman", 2002 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Introduction," "Fishey," "Half Pint Library," "Holly McPolly," "A Slice of Heaven," "Moonlit Hide and Seek," "I Like My Boots," "What Amanda Saw," "Weenie Man," "Sara Says Goodbye"
    - "Big Kid" master, 2003 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Io," "Iolana," "Cantaloupe," "Ooh La La," "Middle of the Little Country Road," "Eat My Breakfast," "Look at Me," "Louise," "Pledge," "Little Seed," "Radiation Man," "Pink on the Inside," "Green Beans," "Here It Comes," "My Sista My Friend," "Nanatime Armadillo Story," "Little Yella Dog," "Belinsky," "I Wish I Were a Princess," "Spinach," "It's Fall," "Space Poetry," "Pillowman," "That's Your Red Wagon," "Rainstick," "I Wish You Well," "Prayer for Peace"
    - "Bid Kid" studio work, 2003 (Box 7)
    - "Big Kid" finals with compression, 2003-08-25 (Box 7)
    - "Motherlode", 2006 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "A Song of You," "To a Maddening Ghost," "Wagoner's Lad," "Living in Quiet Desperation," "Mad World," "Twenty Years to Life," "Mother's Little Helper," "Comfort's Sigh," "My Mama's Hands," "Birdhouse," "Two Days Later," "Learn You Like a Book," "Are We Ever Gonna Have Sex Again?," "Stupid Love!," "Good," "Enuf," "Always a Saint," "Little Bird of Anger," "This Too Will Pass," "You Reward"
    - Sara Hickman and Friends, Crossroads (2), 2006-09-16 (Box 7)
    - "All the Wild Wonders: A Benefit for the Children with Diabetes Foundation", 2007 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Iolana," "Big Trouble"
    - "Rescue Me: Music Benefiting Central Texas Dachshund Rescue", 2007 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Stupid Love," Shake Russell and Jack Saunders - "Two Old Dogs," Trout Fishing in America - "Sleepytime Cartoon"
    - "More Sara Tunes", 2009-02 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "Risk," "148," "Satin Sheets for Alice," "Man Full of Courage"
    - "Sing to Me: A Lullaby Album", 2009 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "It's Alright"
    - "Absence of Blame", 2010 (Box 7)
      These files are digitized master copy WAVs and access copy MP3s. Tracks include: "I'm So Glad You Came Along," "Suitcase," "Size Six Dress," "State of Emergency," "Edentown," "99 Percent," "Blown Away," "Broken," "Before You Change Your Mind," "Juliet and Juliet," "Last Man in the Water," "Last of a Dying Breed," "Love Is There"
    - CD release party, Waterloo Records, 2010-05-11 (Box 7)
    - "The Best of Times: Texas Artists Performing the Music of Sara Hickman", 2011 (Box 7)